# Adam L. Santone, PhD

- Round Rock, TX
- 765-490-8450
- Portfolio
- GitHub

- ≥ adam.santone@gmail.com
- in LinkedIn
- ☆ Scholar
- R<sup>G</sup> ResearchGate

## **Profile**

Senior technical learning experience designer (LXD) and trainer with extensive experience in crafting high-quality educational experiences for challenging material. Strengths include international collaboration, technical translational communication, analytical thinking, forward-looking problem-solving, and practical quantitative analysis skills.

## **Professional Experience**

**ZoomInfo** 2024/04 – present

Data Enablement Lead, Revenue Enablement

- Responsible for the definition and execution of a data enablement strategy & plan to ensure go-to-market (GTM) teams have the knowledge, skill and confidence to enact industry-leading sales velocity
- Supports Data-as-a-Service (DaaS), Data Management, and Data Enrichment through effective knowledge base development, training, and implementation strategy

#### **Technical Education Consultant**

2019/12 - present

2020/10 - 2023/05

- MIT Solve  $\mathscr{D}$ ; Learner//Meets//Future: AI-enabled Assessments Challenge  $\mathscr{D}$
- Ziplines Education ∅; LXD: generative artificial intelligence and prompting
- BioBuilder.org ⊘; LXD & Instructor: synthetic biology & data analysis

#### **Emeritus Institute of Management (Emeritus.org)**

Senior Technical Instructional Designer @

- Designed AI/ML/Data Science courses with world-class faculty, executive partners, & other stakeholders
- Sustained successful relationships with subject-matter experts & external partners
- Designed & developed accessible content, curricula, assessments, custom graphics, videos, visualizations, & interactive experiences in multiple formats for e-learning & video-based training
- Designed custom automation & efficiency tools
- Practiced excellent communication, writing, & editing skills for knowledge transfer & skill development explaining technical content to a wide variety of audiences

## Massachusetts Institute of Technology | Open Learning | J-WEL

2019/05 - 2019/11

Data Science Learning Experience Designer ≥

- Developed & delivered data science instructional content for Uruguayan learners
- Designed, developed, & delivered 20+ data science lessons
- Presented synchronous online instructor-led content weekly to 50+ learners

## Massachusetts Institute of Technology | Lemelson-MIT

Invention Education Program Coordinator ≥

2018/03 – 2019/04

- Created, delivered, & maintained 10+ invention-themed educational products
- Created custom productivity, research, & visualization tools using R and Python
- Led hands-on workshops through instructor-led training

## Florida State University | Learning Systems Institute (LSI)

Professional Development Coordinator & Technical Media Producer &

2012/02 - 2017/07

- Owned the design & development of 350+ short-format STEAM documentary videos tied to state and national learning standards
- Led the development of 50+ mathematics- and science-related 3D models and accompanying curriculum
- Led statewide instructor-led teacher professional development
- Supervised teachers, scientists, and university faculty as workshop staff

Adam L. Santone, PhD 1/2

## Skills

#### R, Python, Quarto, SQL, dplyr

data wrangling, analysis, modeling, visualization, interaction, file manipulation, task automation

#### **Data Visualization**

color theory, UI/UX, interaction design, visual design principles

#### **Team Management**

interpersonal development, communication strategies, project plan development, efficiency tools development

#### **Learning Management Systems**

Canvas, modular learning experience design

## **Instructional Design**

learning objective development, cognitive load management, backward design, pedagogy, andragogy, Articulate, simulations, eLearning, ADDIE, storytelling

#### **Graphics**

Video, Adobe Creative Suite, Photoshop, Premiere, Illustrator, Open Broadcaster Software, DaVinci Resolve

#### **Machine Learning**

principle component analysis, regression, NLP, cluster analysis, classification

## **Quantitative Analysis and Modeling**

exploratory data analysis, correlation, factor analysis

#### **Technical Learning Experience Tools**

Quarto, Markdown, Jupyter, H5P, Trinket, Articulate Storyline

2019

2007

2004

#### Transferable Skills

multimodal communication, time management, process & document organization, workflow development, team interaction, adaptability, initiative, technology literacy

## **Education**

#### **Purdue University**

PhD, Technology | Visual-spatial psychology; simulations & gaming

#### **Purdue University**

MS, Technology | Virtual reality & STEM education

## **Purdue University**

MS, Horticulture | Identification and regulation of touch-induced genes

#### **Henderson State University**

BS, Biology | Genetic characterization of aquatic invertebrates

## Certificates

- Professional Graduate Certificate in Data Science, Harvard Extension School (21FS4F4HAEEW) &
- CS50P: Introduction to Programming with Python, CS50, Harvard University  $\,\mathscr{D}\,$
- CS50 SQL: Introduction to Databases with SQL, CS50, Harvard University  ${\mathscr O}$
- Python for Managers, Columbia Business School Executive Education ℰ

#### **Awards**

#### Pole Star of the Quarter

Emeritus Institute of Management

Awarded 2022 for the development, dissemination, and implementation of custom design process automation tools

#### Outreach

#### Learning Experience Developer (multiple)

BioBuilder.org | MIT Open Learning pk12 Action Group | MIT Full STEAM Ahead

#### Program Fellow, Graduate STEM Fellows in K-12 Education

National Science Foundation (NSF), Purdue University

## Project Counselor, Spaceflight and Life Sciences Training Program

NASA (Kennedy Space Center, FL)

## Volunteering

Peer Mentor 2024/03 – present

MIT ReACT (an initiative of Emerging Talent)

I mentor learners in the Certificate in Computer and Data Science program which includes unemployed or underemployed individuals from refugee, migrant and low income communities located in over 30 countries.

Adam L. Santone, PhD 2/2